<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>c&#39;est la vie</title>
    <link>https://selavy.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on c&#39;est la vie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://selavy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://selavy.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selavy.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a static site engine written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 Cobra Viper J Walter Weatherman Cast  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Pearls: Chapter 4</title>
      <link>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 18:51:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch4/</guid>
      <description>Problems from Column #4: Writing Correct Programs
Lessons  Consider using formal verification methods on tricky functions Loop invariants are a helpful tool  Problem #1 As laborious as our proof of binary search was, it is still unfinished by some standards. How would you prove that the program is free of run-time errors (such as division by zero, word overflow, variables out of declared range, or array indices out of bounds)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Pearls: Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 20:28:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch3/</guid>
      <description>Problems from Column #3: Data Structures Programs
Lessons  Proper view of data structures programs ** The data a system is to process gives deep insight into a good module structure ** Understand the input, the output, and the intermediate data structures Separate data from control (e.g. Model+View+Controller) Don&amp;rsquo;t write a big program when a little one will do ** The more general problem may be easier to solve (Polya&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Inventor&amp;rsquo;s Paradox&amp;rdquo;)  Problem #1 As the second edition of this book goes to press, individual income in the United States is taxed at five different rates, the maximum of which is around forty percent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Pearls: Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 19:01:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch2/</guid>
      <description>Problems for Column #2: &amp;ldquo;Aha! Algorithms&amp;rdquo;
Lessons  Break problem down into primitives for which there are known algorithms. &amp;ldquo;A Problem Solver&amp;rsquo;s Perspective&amp;rdquo;: Good programmers are a little bit lazy: they sit back and wait for an insight rather than rushing forward with their first idea.  Problem #1 Consider the problem of finding all the anagrmas of a given input word. How would you solve this problem given only the word and the dictionary?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Pearls: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 20:47:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selavy.github.io/posts/prog-pearls-ch1/</guid>
      <description>Some notes and solutions to the Column #1: &amp;ldquo;Cracking the Oyster&amp;rdquo; in Programming Pearls by Jon Bentley.
Lessons  Ask the right question. Similar to &amp;ldquo;5 Whys&amp;rdquo;; make sure you understand the real problem. Look for simple designs
 &amp;ldquo;A designer knows he has arrived at perfection now when there is no longer anything to add, but when there is no longer anything to take away.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Antoine de Saint-Exupéry</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>